Shad, John S. R. John S. R. Shad papers, 1972-1989 (inclusive): A Finding Aid
John S. R. Shad papers, 1972-1989 (inclusive)
- II. Congressional testimony, 1981-1987
  - Opening Statement before the Subcommittee on Conversation, Credit, and Rural Development of the House Committee on Agriculture concerning guidelines for futures on non-diversified stock indices,February 8, 1984. (Box Box 7, f. 13)
  - Opening Statement before the Subcommittee on Conversation, Credit, and Rural Development of the House Committee on Agriculture concerning guidelines for futures on non-diversified stock indices, February 8, 1984 (speaking copy). (Box Box 7, f. 14)
  - Oral testimony before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce [SEC FY 1983 results and ongoing efforts], February 23, 1984. (Box Box 7, f. 15)
  - Oral testimony before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce [SEC FY 1983 results and ongoing efforts], February 23, 1984 (speaking copy). (Box Box 7, f. 16)
  - Written statement before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce [SEC FY 1983 results and ongoing efforts], February 23, 1984. (Box Box 7, f. 17)
  - Written statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies of the Senate Committee on Appropriations [SEC FY 1985 budget request], March 7, 1984. (Box Box 7, f. 18)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer, and Monetary Affairs of the House Committee on Government Operations concerning the activities of deposit brokers, March 14, 1984. (Box Box 7, f. 19)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer, and Monetary Affairs of the House Committee on Government Operations concerning the activities of deposit brokers, March 14, 1984 (speaking copy). (Box Box 7, f. 20)
  - Written statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer, and Monetary Affairs of the House Committee on Government Operations concerning the activities of deposit brokers, March 14, 1984. (Box Box 7, f. 21)
  - Written statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies of the House Committee on Appropriations [SEC FY 1985 budget request], March 16, 1984. (Box Box 7, f. 22)
  - Opening statement before the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs concerning S. 2181 and S. 2134 [reform regulation of financial services industries], March 21, 1984. (Box Box 7, f. 23)
  - Opening statement before the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs concerning S. 2181 and S. 2134 [reform regulation of financial services industries], March 21, 1984 (speaking copy). (Box Box 7, f. 24)
  - Written statement before the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs concerning S. 2181 and S. 2134 [reform regulation of financial services industries], March 21, 1984. (Box Box 7, f. 25)
  - Opening statement before the House Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance concerning the SEC Advisory Committee on Tender Offers, March 28, 1984. (Box Box 7, f. 26)
  - Written statement before the House Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance concerning the SEC Advisory Committee on Tender Offers, March 28, 1984. (Box Box 7, f. 27)
  - Opening statement before the Securities Subcommittee of the Senate Banking Committee concerning the Insider Trading Sanctions Act,April 3, 1984. (Box Box 7, f. 28)
  - Opening statement before the Securities Subcommittee of the Senate Banking Committee concerning the Insider Trading Sanctions Act, April 3, 1984 (speaking copy). (Box Box 7, f. 29)
  - Written statement before the Securities Subcommittee of the Senate Banking Committee concerning the Insider Trading Sanctions Act, April 3, 1984. (Box Box 7, f. 30)
  - Opening statement before the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs [four proposals to amend federal securities laws],October 2, 1984. (Box Box 7, f. 31)
  - Opening statement before the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs [four proposals to amend federal securities laws], October 2, 1984 (speaking copy). (Box Box 7, f. 32)
  - Written statement before the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs [four proposals to amend federal securities laws], October 2, 1984. (Box Box 7, f. 33)
  - Opening statement before the House Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations of the Committee on Energy and Commerce on the accounting profession, March 6, 1985. (Box Box 7, f. 34)
  - Opening statement before the House Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations of the Committee on Energy and Commerce on the accounting profession, March 6, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 7, f. 35)
  - Written Statement before the House Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations of the Committee on Energy and Commerce on the accounting profession, March 6, 1985. (Box Box 7, f. 36)
  - Oral Statement before the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning EDGAR (Electronic Data Gathering, Analysis and Retrieval System), March 14, 1985. (Box Box 7, f. 37)
  - Written Statement before the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning EDGAR (Electronic Data Gathering, Analysis and Retrieval System), March 14, 1985. (Box Box 7, f. 38)
  - Oral testimony before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce on authorization of the SEC, March 21, 1985. (Box Box 7, f. 39)
  - Oral testimony before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce on authorization of the SEC, March 21, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 7, f. 40)
  - Written statement before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce on authorization of the SEC, March 21, 1985. (Box Box 7, f. 41)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer and Monetary Affairs of the House Committee on Government Operations on the recommendations of the Bush Task Group on Regulation of Financial Services, March 26, 1985. (Box Box 7, f. 42)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer and Monetary Affairs of the House Committee on Government Operations on the recommendations of the Bush Task Group on Regulation of Financial Services, March 26, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 7, f. 43)
  - Written statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer and Monetary Affairs of the House Committee on Government Operations on the recommendations of the Bush Task Group on Regulation of Financial Services, March 26, 1985 (revised). (Box Box 7, f. 44)
  - Oral Statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice and State, the Judiciary and Related Agencies of the House Committee on Appropriations [regarding SEC FY 1986 budget request], March 27, 1985. (Box Box 7, f. 45)
  - Oral Statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice and State, the Judiciary and Related Agencies of the House Committee on Appropriations [regarding SEC FY 1986 budget request], March 27, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 7, f. 46)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer and Monetary Affairs of the House Committee on Government Operations concerning regulation of the government securities market, April 3, 1985. (Box Box 7, f. 47)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer and Monetary Affairs of the House Committee on Government Operations concerning regulation of the government securities market, April 3, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 7, f. 48)
  - Written statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer and Monetary Affairs of the House Committee on Government Operations concerning regulation of the government securities market, April 3, 1985. (Box Box 7, f. 49)
  - Opening statement before the Senate Subcommittee on Securities [hearing on tender offers], April 4, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 7, f. 50)
  - Written statement before the Senate Subcommittee on Securities [hearing on tender offers], April 4, 1985. (Box Box 7, f. 51)
  - Oral testimony before the Subcommittee on Securities of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs concerning SEC reauthorization, oversight, and government securities, April 17, 1985. (Box Box 8, f. 1)
  - Oral testimony before the Subcommittee on Securities of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs concerning SEC reauthorization, oversight, and government securities, April 17, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 2)
  - Written statement before the Subcommittee on Securities of the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs concerning SEC reauthorization, oversight, and government securities, April 17, 1985. (Box Box 8, f. 3)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Government Information, Justice, and Agriculture of the House Committee on Government Operations concerning EDGAR (Electronic Data Gathering, Analysis and Retrieval System), April 29, 1985. (Box Box 8, f. 4)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Government Information, Justice, and Agriculture of the House Committee on Government Operations concerning EDGAR (Electronic Data Gathering, Analysis and Retrieval System), April 29, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 5)
  - Written statement before the Subcommittee on Government Information, Justice, and Agriculture of the House Committee on Government Operations concerning EDGAR (Electronic Data Gathering, Analysis and Retrieval System), April 29, 1985. (Box Box 8, f. 6)
  - Oral statement before the House Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance concerning changes in the securities markets, May 2, 1985. (Box Box 8, f. 7)
  - Oral statement before the House Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance concerning changes in the securities markets, May 2, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 8)
  - Written statement before the House Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance concerning changes in the securities markets, May 2, 1985. (Box Box 8, f. 9)
  - Opening statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer and Monetary Affairs of the House Committee on Government Operations concerning the government securities markets, May 15, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 10)
  - Written statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer and Monetary Affairs of the House Committee on Government Operations concerning the government securities markets, May 15, 1985. (Box Box 8, f. 11)
  - Opening statement before the House Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance concerning tender offers, May 23, 1985. (Box Box 8, f. 12)
  - Opening statement before the House Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance concerning tender offers, May 23, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 13)
  - Written statement before the House Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance concerning tender offers, May 23, 1985. (Box Box 8, f. 14)
  - Opening statement before the House Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations concerning oversight of the self-regulatory organization, June 17, 1985. (Box Box 8, f. 15)
  - Opening statement before the House Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations concerning oversight of the self-regulatory organization, June 17, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 16)
  - Written statement before the House Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations concerning oversight of the self-regulatory organization, June 17, 1985. (Box Box 8, f. 17)
  - Opening statement before the House Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance concerning regulation of the government securities market, June 20, 1985. (Box Box 8, f. 18)
  - Opening statement before the House Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance concerning regulation of the government securities market, June 20, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 19)
  - Report to the House Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance concerning regulation of the government securities market, June 20, 1985. (Box Box 8, f. 20)
  - Opening statement before Subcommittee on Economic Resources, Competitiveness, and Security Economics of the Joint Economic Committee concerning General Dynamics, June 28, 1985. (Box Box 8, f. 21)
  - Written statement of Clarence Sampson, Chief Accountant, and Gary Lynch, Director, Division of Enforcement, Securities and Exchange Commission before the Subcommittee on Economic Resources, Competitiveness, and Security Economics of the Joint Economic Committee concerning Navy shipbuilding by General Dynamics Corporation, June 28, 1985. (Box Box 8, f. 22)
  - Opening statement before the House Subcommittee on Domestic Monetary Policy concerning the regulation of the government securities market, July 9, 1985. (Box Box 8, f. 23)
  - Opening statement before the House Subcommittee on Domestic Monetary Policy concerning the regulation of the government securities market, July 9, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 24)
  - Opening statement before the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning S&L [Savings and Loan] accounting and financial reporting, July 19, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 25)
  - Written statement before the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning S&L [Savings and Loan] accounting and financial reporting, July 19, 1985. (Box Box 8, f. 26)
  - Oral testimony before the Subcommittee on Criminal Justice of the House Committee on the Judiciary concerning the private civil liability provisions of RICO (Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organizations) Act, October 2, 1985. (Box Box 8, f. 27)
  - Oral testimony before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning tender offer regulation, October 24, 1985. (Box Box 8, f. 28)
  - Opening statement before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning tender offer regulation, October 24, 1985 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 29)
  - Summary of testimony before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning tender offer regulation, October 24, 1985. (Box Box 8, f. 30)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice and State, the Judiciary and Related Agencies of the House Committee on Appropriations, February 21, 1986. (Box Box 8, f. 31)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice and State, the Judiciary and Related Agencies of the House Committee on Appropriations, February 21, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 32)
  - Written statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice and State, the Judiciary and Related Agencies of the House Committee on Appropriations, February 21, 1986. (Box Box 8, f. 33)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce—Oversight Hearing, March 5, 1986. (Box Box 8, f. 34)
  - Written statement before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce—Oversight Hearing, March 5, 1986. (Box Box 8, f. 35)
  - “Commission Policy on Takeovers”—Edited speech copy and notes, March 12, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 36)
  - Opening statement before the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning bank accounting and financial reporting, April 24, 1986. (Box Box 8, f. 37)
  - Opening statement before the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning bank accounting and financial reporting, April 24, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 38)
  - Opening statement of Gary Lynch, Director, Division of Enforcement, Securities and Exchange Commission, before the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning bank accounting and financial reporting, April 24, 1986. (Box Box 8, f. 39)
  - Opening statement of Clarence Sampson, Chief Accountant, Securities and Exchange Commission, before the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning bank accounting and financial reporting, April 24, 1986. (Box Box 8, f. 40)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice and State, the Judiciary and Related Agencies of the Senate Committee on Appropriations, April 14, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 41)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer, and Monetary Affairs of the House Committee on Government Operations concerning the regulation of financial services, May 22, 1986 (postponed) (Box Box 8, f. 42)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning investment advisers and financial planners, June 11, 1986. (Box Box 8, f. 43)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning investment advisers and financial planners, June 11, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 44)
  - Opening statement Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning insider trading violations, June 18, 1986. (Box Box 8, f. 45)
  - Opening statement Subcommittee on Telecommunications, Consumer Protection, and Finance of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning insider trading violations, June 18, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 46)
  - Opening statement before the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce, June 23, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 47)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer, and Monetary Affairs of the House Committee on Government Operations concerning the regulation of financial services, July 23, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 48)
  - Opening statement before the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning insider trading, December 11, 1986. (Box Box 8, f. 49)
  - Opening statement before the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations of the House Committee on Energy and Commerce concerning insider trading, December 11, 1986 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 50)
  - Opening statement before the Senate Committee on the Budget concerning securities law aspects of Federal Government loan sales, February 19, 1987 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 51)
  - Oral statement before the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice and State, the Judiciary and Related Agencies of the House Committee on Appropriations, February 24, 1987 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 52)
  - Opening statement before the Senate Securities Subcommittee—SEC Reauthorization Hearing, May 13, 1987 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 53)
  - Oral statement before Senate Foreign Relations Committee—Confirmation hearing for nomination as Ambassador to the Kingdom of the Netherlands, May 28, 1987 (speaking copy). (Box Box 8, f. 54)
- III. Briefing materials, 1972-1989
  This series contains a variety of documentation gathered by Mr. Shad’s Securities and Exchange Commission staff to prepare him for appearances before congressional committees. The briefing materials include copies of S. E. C. regulatory announcements and policy statements; advisory committee reports; and comment letters and reports submitted by the securities exchanges, government agencies, and other interested parties. The documents date from 1972 to 1977.
  These briefing materials provided Chairman Shad with an overview of numerous regulatory issues that stemmed from changes mandated by the Securities Acts Amendments of 1975. The 1975 Amendments charged the S. E. C. with making dramatic changes in the securities industry, including the development of a National Market System that would change the relationship between the New York Stock Exchange, the regional exchanges, and the National Association of Securities Dealers; changes in the rules regarding off-board trading; and the creation of system-wide automated reporting mechanisms. The specific subjects covered in the briefing materials are: Exchange Off-Board Trading Rules; National Market System; Consolidated Transaction Reporting System; Composite Quotation System; Commission Rates, Membership and Member Trading; and Section 31(b) of the Securities Acts Amendments of 1975. Many of these issues remained unresolved during Mr. Shad’s S. E. C. chairmanship.
  The series also contains briefing materials prepared for Mr. Shad during his tenure as chairman of Drexel Burnham Lambert. In October 1989, Mr. Shad traveled to Singapore to meet and reassure current and prospective clients. The materials include itineraries, suggested talking points, and background information on the individuals and companies with whom Mr. Shad met.
  - Background material relating to Exchange Off-Board Trading Rules
    - SEC Staff Report: Rule 394 Reprinted in Study of the Securities Industry Hearings Before the Subcommittee on Commerce and Finance of the House Committee on Inter-state and Foreign Commerce, H.R. Serial No. 92-37e, 92d Cong., 2d Sess., pt. 6 at 3293-3372 (1972) (Box Box 9, f. 1)
    - Securities and Exchange Commission, Statement on The Future Structure of the Securities Markets, February 1972. (Box Box 9, f. 2)
    - Securities and Exchange Commission, Policy Statement on the Structure of a Central Market System, March 1973. (Box Box 9, f. 3)
    - Securities Exchange Act Release No. 11521 (Request for Public Comment on Issues Associated with Off-Board Trading Rules), July 2, 1975. (Box Box 9, f. 4)
    - Letter from Congressman John E. Moss, Chairman, Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations of the House Committee on Interstate and Foreign Commerce, August 29, 1975. (Box Box 9, f. 5)
    - Comment letter, United States Department of Justice, July 31, 1975. (Box Box 9, f. 6)
    - Comment letter, American Stock Exchange, July 30, 1975. (Box Box 9, f. 7)
    - Comment letter, Chicago Board Options Exchange, July 31, 1975. (Box Box 9, f. 8)
    - Comment letter, Securities Industry Association, August 4, 1975. (Box Box 9, f. 9)
    - Comment letter, Donald E. Weeden, Chairman, Weeden & Co., August 14, 1975. (Box Box 9, f. 10)
    - Report of the Securities and Exchange Commission on Rules of National Securities Exchanges which Limit or Condition the Ability of Members to effect Transactions otherwise than on such Exchanges (Pursuant to Section 11A (C) (4) (A) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934), September 2, 1975 with Appendices. (Box Box 9, f. 11)
    - Appendix A: Texts of Rules of National Securities Exchanges which Limit or Condition the Ability of Members to effect Transactions otherwise than on such Exchange. (Box Box 9, f. 12)
    - Appendix B: Off-Board Trading Rules of the New York Stock Exchange. (Box Box 9, f. 13)
    - Appendix C: Off-Board Trading Rules of Other Securities Exchanges. (Box Box 9, f. 14)